

Laurynas Karvelis

Tel: +44 7713 167071

Email: <u>hello@explosive-brains.com</u>

Github: http://github.com/laurynas-karvelis

Location: Central London

PROFILE

A dedicated SENIOR NODE.JS JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER delivering beautiful and exciting web applications with passion for over 12 years. With attention to detail and uncompromised quality of work a every-day skills such as object oriented Javascript, Node.js, an entire MEAN stack, CI and other cutting ed tech to build fast, user friendly, intuitive and well-tested RESTful backend services and single page web applications. Projects delivered using Agile, Scrum methodologies. Now seeking for a rewarding contract opportunity as a SENIOR BACKEND DEVELOPER to achieve client oriented results.

RELEVANT EXPERTISE

- Node.js (4 years), Express.js, Sails.js, Bluebird, Mongoose, Mocha, Chai, Swagger, Babel;
- Angular.js (2 years), ngResource, Angular UI-Router, Karma + Jasmine, Protractor;
- Javascript (8 years), OOP design patterns, Angular.js, Node.js, Sails.js, MEAN stack, Grunt, Bower, Native JS, jQuery;
- MongoDb (3 years), MySQL (8 years), CouchDb;
- HTML5 (8 years of (x)HTML), Jade, Mustache, Handlebars, EJS; Web Canvas, W3C);
- CSS3 (8 years of CSS), Sass, Less; Bootstrap, Foundation, Semantic UI;
- Git, Jira, Confluence, Crucible, FogBugz, SVN;
- Code testing Mocha + Chai, Codecov, Karma, Jasmine, Protractor;
- Nginx, Apache, Redis, continuous integration, continuous delivery;
- Agile, Scrum methodologies, code reviews, pair programming;
- Meeting tight deadlines, capable of working under pressure.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Innovated business application development by developing front-facing, uncompromised quality tools that are being used by some of Fortune 500 companies.
- Worked on two of the first pioneering Facebook real money online gambling applications frontends using latest Facebook API features that were not even open to the public.
- Successfully re-designed and re-developed startpage platform for providers like Microsoft's Bing, Yahoo and Ask. The platform serves more than 10 million visitors each month. Created entire Javascript Application development framework and built proprietary web applications for Facebook Twitter, Gmail and 10 others on top of it. Increased user's lifetime value for company and it's partners.
- Re-designed UI for existing SEO web application. Created top-notch Node.js chart processing server for reporting system. Created internal decision making system to calculate website's SEO ratings from more than 100 different criterias by aggregating 200 GB MySQL data for faster data processing and re-presentation. Therefore increased customers' satisfaction rate significantly.
- Developed and maintained bespoke CMS solution and launched over 20 websites, web portals for various lithuanian clients. The CMS helped dozens new and existing businesses to increase thei sales and brand recognition.

Created CRM, billing and server management system for Lithuanian web hosting company.
 This solution made company one of the first fully automated web hosting companies in Lithuania with reduced support staff costs.

EMPLOYMENT

Senior Node.js developer @ Dixons Carphone Warehouse (www.dixonscarphone.com)

Apr 2016 - Sep 2016

- ES6 Node.js RESTful service development with NoSQL datastores;
- Heavy use of Promise based async task chaining;
- Unit, integration testing, 95% average code coverage, CI & CD.

Senior Frontend developer @ Essence digital (www.essencedigital.com)
Nov 2015 - Mid Feb 2016

- Internal advertising management platform as a single page web application;
- Frontend web application with Angular.js and Angular Material;
- Continuous integration, and code testing with Karma + Jasmine, Docker.

Co-founder, chief product officer @ Geektastic.com (www.geektastic.com) Sep 2014 - Oct 2015

- Developer technical assessment and hiring platform using Angular.js, Sails.js, MongoDB;
- UX and UI development using Twitter Bootstrap, Semantic UI;
- Entire website developed solely by one developer.

Senior Frontend developer @ The Press Association (www.pressassociation.com)
May 2014 - Aug 2014

- E-commerce website using Angular.js and Sails.js (node.js);
- Unit testing with Karma, Functional testing with Protractor + Selenium.

Senior Frontend developer @ Signal Noise (signal-noise.co.uk) Apr 2014 - May 2014

- Backbone MVP project for EE big data analysis and presentation;
- HTML canvas for mobile device performance, animations, Easel.js

Senior Frontend developer @ Gamesys (www.gamesyscorporate.com)
Jun 2013 – Jan 2014

- Virgin Poker Facebook app development using Backbone.js;
- TDD via Jasmine + Grunt; Maven; Hudson.

Senior Frontend developer @ Bonzagaming (www.bonzagaming.com)
Oct 2012 – Feb 2013, Mar 2013 – Jul 2013 (extension)

- Greenfield responsive Facebook app development from the architecture till it's release using Backbone.js on frontend;
- Node.js + Express.js for mockup backend testing;
- TDD and functional testing using Jasmine and Mocha + Chai spinning Selenium via SauceLabs.

Senior Frontend developer @ DeLaRue plc. (www.delarue.com) Mar 2012 – Sep 2012

- Greenfield Javascript OOP with frontend models, Zend Framework project using SOAP webservices
 as data-source using service/mapper/entity layers. It is a NDA project, but these were my technica
 responsibilities:
 - o Modular jQuery frontend utilising best object oriented programming practices with backbone is to control models, views etc.:
 - Numerous jQuery plugins created, browser specific memory leak fixes for various external jQuery libraries; Javascript code performance improvements
 - Utilisation of Twitter Bootstrap CSS and Javascript library, combining that with backend Zend Framework dynamic form generations;
 - Superb use of latest, high-end Javascript technologies while in rapid Agile application development.

Head of Search (Backend and Frontend developer) @ Zugo Services Ltd. (www.zugo.com) Feb 2011 – Feb 2012

- Responsible to create a specific PHP backend platform delivery framework for increased speed
 (handles 10 millions of visitors each month in cluster). Delivered custom browser-based Javascript
 application development framework with Facebook, Twitter, Gmail and other 10 additional
 applications purely written on top of this JS framework and jQuery;
- R&D of new startpage platform, HTML5 canvas animations experiments, physics engine in Javascri implementation for visuals;
- Took care for this project from specification till launch, helped other developers by teaching them.

PHP backend/frontend programmer @ Analytics SEO (www.analyticsseo.com) Aug 2010 – Feb 2011

- Created dedicated Node.js server which utilises Highcharts Javascript library in browser-less imital DOM environment that is capable to export statistical charts automatically into PNG or any other type graph images;
- Responsible to develop a new backend decision making system for company online service by aggregating 200GB in size MySQL database, optimising SQL queries and database itself;
- Re-developed whole frontend UI for the customers by representing aggregated data in nice and clean way.

Senior frontend programmer @ Laisvalaikio Dovanos, UAB (www.laisvalaikiodovanos.lt) Apr 2009 — Nov 2009

- Stabilised internal CRM system and frontend online shop by adding new features, fixing bugs left be another company which first created this bespoke system. Took care of UI tests using Google AB testing, therefore managed to increase conversion rates for online store;
- Redeveloped frontend UI for the clients by representing aggregated data in nice and clean way;
- Support of this bespoke system in 4 countries sharing similar code base, managing and prioritising each country feature/bug requests.

Senior frontend developer and Project manager @ Made.By, UAB (www.by.lt) Mar 2007 - Mar 2009

- Providing best online marketing solutions for the company. Gathering project requirements, delive
 of finished project, close work with freelance designers, company web developers;
- Responsible for bespoke CMS development and maintenance, delivered and launched over 20 projects with this CMS by adapting it to each project using Agile methodology.

PHP developer @ E-vaizdas.net, UAB (www.e-vaizdas.net)
May 2003 – Jun 2006

 Responsible to create completely new bespoke CRM, billing and automated web hosting server management system. Features like server farm remote "one-click" control, automated customer accounts' management, automated hosting account controls; Company website development and maintenance, new billing methods' implementations were my duties.

PERSONAL SKILLS AND COMPETENCES

Languages:

- English (fluent)
- German (spoken)
- Russian (spoken)
- Lithuanian (mother tongue)
- Portuguese (spoken)

EDUCATION

Master's degree @ International Business School at Vilnius University Feb 2009 – Feb 2011

Title of qualification: International Marketing and Business

International classification: Master's degree

Bachelor's degree @ Kaunas University of Technology Sep 2004 – Jul 2008

Title of qualification awarded: Informatics

Title of specialization: Information System Design International classification: Bachelor's degree